Captain Jack is back!
Pirates of the Caribbean: Dead Man's Chest is a adventure,
fantasy, action film directed by Gore Verbinski.
Jack's got a blood debt to pay: he owes his soul to the legendary
Davy Jones, ghastly Ruler of the Ocean Depths.
But ever-crafty Jack isn't about to go down without a fight.
Jack Sparrow, played by Johnny Depp.
Will Turner, played by Orlando Bloom.
Elizabeth Swann, played by Keira Knightley.
William "Bootstrap Bill" Turner, played by Stellan Skarsgård.
Davy Jones, played by Bill Nighy.
James Norrington, played by Jack Davenport.
Pirates of the Caribbean: Dead Man's Chest is a 2006 American fantasy swashbuckler film directed by Gore
Verbinski, written by Ted Elliott and Terry Rossio, and produced by Jerry Bruckheimer.
The sequel to Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl (2003), it is
the second installment in the Pirates of the Caribbean film series.
It is set a year after the first film and follows Captain Jack Sparrow who owes a debt to Davy Jones (Bill Nighy),
the ghastly captain of the Flying Dutchman, and being marked for death and pursued by the Kraken.
Meanwhile, the wedding of Will Turner (Orlando Bloom) and Elizabeth Swann (Keira Knightley) is interrupted by Lord Cutler
Beckett (Tom Hollander), who wants Turner to acquire Jack's magic compass in a bid to find the Dead Man's Chest.
Two sequels to Pirates of the Caribbean: The Curse of the Black Pearl were conceived in 2004,
with Elliott and Rossio developing a story arc that would span both films.
Filming took place from February to September 2005 in Palos Verdes, Saint Vincent and the
Grenadines, Dominica, and The Bahamas, as well as on sets constructed at Walt Disney Studios.
It was shot back-to-back with the third film of
the series, At World's End (2007).
With a production budget of $225 million, it was the most
expensive film ever made at the time of its release.
Dead Man's Chest premiered at the Disneyland Resort on June 24, 2006, and was
released in the United States on July 7, to mixed reviews from critics.
The film broke several records at the time, including the opening-weekend record in the United States with $136 million and the fastest film to gross over $1 billion at the worldwide box
office (63 days), and became the highest-grossing film of 2006, the third highest-grossing film of all time at the time of its release, and the highest-grossing film in the series.
It was also the highest-grossing film released by Disney
until it was surpassed by Toy Story 3 in 2010.
The film received four nominations at the 79th Academy
Awards (winning Best Visual Effects).
The film explores themes of witch, daughter, ship, exotic island, bondage.